<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Home on Your Guide to Machu Picchu</title>
    <link>https://www.guidetomachupicchu.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Home on Your Guide to Machu Picchu</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2020 23:27:14 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.guidetomachupicchu.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>10 Steps to creating the ideal Machu Picchu trip</title>
      <link>https://www.guidetomachupicchu.com/blogs/2020-01-22-10-steps-to-creating-the-ideal-machu-picchu-trip/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2020 23:27:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.guidetomachupicchu.com/blogs/2020-01-22-10-steps-to-creating-the-ideal-machu-picchu-trip/</guid>
      <description>Step by Step guide to creating your own Machu Picchu Trip
Visiting Machu Picchu with the mandatory times, train times, bus departures etc&amp;hellip;did not become easier but not everyone wants to pay a travel agent to make sure you visit Machu Picchu in the best way possible. For the intrepid travelers among us, following a 10 step guide to follow to make sure you make the most out of your time at Machu Picchu.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What are the temperatures like at Machu Picchu?</title>
      <link>https://www.guidetomachupicchu.com/questions/2020-01-12-what-are-the-temperatures-like-at-machu-picchu/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2020 20:23:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.guidetomachupicchu.com/questions/2020-01-12-what-are-the-temperatures-like-at-machu-picchu/</guid>
      <description>Machu Picchu weather most of the time is pleasantly warm during the day. Night times do not get really cold either except for some nights in July and August. Temperatures in Machu Picchu and Aguas Calientes range between 50 and 75 degrees Fahrenheit (12 and 24 degrees Celsius). More so than temperature, weather at Machu Picchu is distinguished more by its dry season and wet season. Humidity levels are always high making sensational temperature often higher than the real ones.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Best time of the year to visit Machu Picchu</title>
      <link>https://www.guidetomachupicchu.com/blogs/2020-01-12-best-time-of-the-year-to-visit-machu-picchu/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2020 20:03:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.guidetomachupicchu.com/blogs/2020-01-12-best-time-of-the-year-to-visit-machu-picchu/</guid>
      <description>Best time to visit Machu Picchu is in the dry season June, July and August busiest months March and November, transition months Best time of the year; April, May, September and October  Machu Picchu can without issues be visited all year round and open 365 days in the year. This being said, being an outdoors location, Machu Picchu is subject to the local weather conditions. As you will read almost anywhere; the best time of the year to visit Machu Picchu is the dry season.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Is Inca Rail cheaper than Peru Rail?</title>
      <link>https://www.guidetomachupicchu.com/questions/2020-01-10-is-inca-rail-cheaper-than-peru-rail/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2020 18:33:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.guidetomachupicchu.com/questions/2020-01-10-is-inca-rail-cheaper-than-peru-rail/</guid>
      <description>Inca Rail used to be quite some cheaper than Peru Rail but nowadays the difference is only felt in the deluxe version of the train; the First Class Train. The starting level, Voyager you can book for US$59 to US$72 one way and the Superior 360° Train from US$77 to US$86 one way. The difference with similar levels with Peru Rail is only a couple of Dollars. The First Class Train goes at US$200 one way.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How much does the Train to Machu Picchu cost?</title>
      <link>https://www.guidetomachupicchu.com/questions/2020-01-10-how-much-does-the-train-to-machu-picchu-cost/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2020 18:32:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.guidetomachupicchu.com/questions/2020-01-10-how-much-does-the-train-to-machu-picchu-cost/</guid>
      <description>Peru Rail has three train types to Machu Picchu. The Expedition Train costs between US$54 and US$ 68 one way and the Vistadome between US$77 to US$95 one way. Prices fluctuate depending on the departure times and train stations. The upgrade to the Hiram Bingham is a little steep at US$495 one way but you get a luxury train, meals and drinks in return.
https://www.perurail.com/
Related Content : Details on trains to Machu Picchu  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How much does the Machu Picchu entrance ticket cost?</title>
      <link>https://www.guidetomachupicchu.com/questions/2020-01-10-how-much-does-the-machu-picchu-entrance-ticket-cost/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2020 18:22:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.guidetomachupicchu.com/questions/2020-01-10-how-much-does-the-machu-picchu-entrance-ticket-cost/</guid>
      <description>The entrance tickets for Machu Picchu in 2020 will remain the same as in 2019; US$46 for the normal entrance ticket and US$61 including either Huayna Picchu or Montaña. For children under 8 years of age the entrance is free and children between 8 and 12 years of age pay US$21 and US$36 for the ticket that includes Huayna Picchu or Montaña. These prices are calculated with an exchange rate of US$1 = S/.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>More Machu Picchu Travel Information</title>
      <link>https://www.guidetomachupicchu.com/blogs/2020-01-09-external-machu-picchu-travel-information/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2020 05:05:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.guidetomachupicchu.com/blogs/2020-01-09-external-machu-picchu-travel-information/</guid>
      <description>Following you can find some great external links to other websites with some great information on Machu Picchu.
Complementary routes in Machu Picchu Here you can find more details on the complementary visitors circuits at Machu Picchu.
https://www.howtotraveltomachupicchu.com/travel-tips/alternatives-climbing-huayna-picchu
The Temples of Machu Picchu Machu Picchu is home to several temples and special constructions; here we will tell you more about the ones you should not miss during your visit.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Traveling to Machu Picchu; 10 practical tips for visitors</title>
      <link>https://www.guidetomachupicchu.com/blogs/2020-01-09-traveling-to-machu-picchu-10-practical-tips-for-visitors/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2020 04:30:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.guidetomachupicchu.com/blogs/2020-01-09-traveling-to-machu-picchu-10-practical-tips-for-visitors/</guid>
      <description>Machu Picchu Visitor Tips Machu Picchu is a unique and adventurous destination but is perhaps not as easy to get to as some of the other bucket list destinations that often get listed. For the Colosseum you fly to Rome and the rest is all pretty straight forward. For Christ the Redeemer you fly to Rio and can even take a taxi there. For Machu Picchu this is not that simple making that one would need at least two (preferably more) days in Peru to see Machu Picchu.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Machu Picchu Altitude</title>
      <link>https://www.guidetomachupicchu.com/blogs/2020-01-07-machu-picchu-altitude/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2020 23:30:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.guidetomachupicchu.com/blogs/2020-01-07-machu-picchu-altitude/</guid>
      <description>Machu Picchu is located on 7,350ft, much lower than Cusco Most visitors have little or no issues with the altitude in Machu Picchu The lower altitude and proximity to the jungle makes the Machu Picchu climate warmer and more humid The lower altitude is the reason some visitors prefer first to visit machu Picchu and then Cusco Machu Picchu is located about 100km (3 hours) from Cusco  Cusco is infamous for its high altitude (almost 12,000ft (3,500m) and the chances of getting altitude sickness.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LATEST UPDATE; Train services to Machu Picchu reinstated</title>
      <link>https://www.guidetomachupicchu.com/blogs/2020-01-06-latest-update-train-services-to-machu-picchu-reinstated/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2020 14:37:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.guidetomachupicchu.com/blogs/2020-01-06-latest-update-train-services-to-machu-picchu-reinstated/</guid>
      <description>Train services to Machu Picchu have been reinstated according the normal schedule All visitors can complete their Machu Picchu visit as planned Water levels of the Vilcanota River have returned to normal levels The train companies remain vigilant of the situation January and February are the months with most rain in the Machu Picchu region  January 6, 2020 This morning Ferrocarril Transandino S.A, the company that runs the train tracks to Machu Picchu, informed the train companies Peru Rail and Inca Rail they can resume train services to and from Machu Picchu according to the normal schedule and frequencies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Latest Update - Machu Picchu inaccessible by train</title>
      <link>https://www.guidetomachupicchu.com/blogs/2020-01-06-latest-update-machu-picchu-inaccessible/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2020 02:44:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.guidetomachupicchu.com/blogs/2020-01-06-latest-update-machu-picchu-inaccessible/</guid>
      <description>TRAIN SERVICES TO MACHU PICCHU HAVE RESUMED
Related Content : TRAIN SERVICES TO MACHU PICCHU HAVE RESUMED  January 6, 2020 - Yesterday a press release was emitted by Ferrocarril Transandino S.A, the company that runs the train tracks to Machu Picchu, that till further notice there would not be any trains allowed to travel to Machu Picchu. This is because the rising waters of the Vilcanota (Urubamba) River are threatening the train tracks that run besides them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Latest News; Machu Picchu Temporarily Not accessible</title>
      <link>https://www.guidetomachupicchu.com/blogs/2020-01-06-latest-new-machu-picchu-temporarily-not-accessible/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2020 00:44:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.guidetomachupicchu.com/blogs/2020-01-06-latest-new-machu-picchu-temporarily-not-accessible/</guid>
      <description>TRAIN SERVICES TO MACHU PICCHU HAVE RESUMED
Related Content : TRAIN SERVICES TO MACHU PICCHU HAVE RESUMED   Machu Picchu temporarily not accessible by train Not clear how hikes to Machu Picchu will be affected Measure because of increased water level of Vilcanota River Start of the rainy season- measure in place till water levels decrease  Cusco; January 5, 2020 - The Ferrocarril Transandino S.A., the company that operates the train tracks between Cusco and Machu Picchu (Aguas Calientes) has released a statement today informing all passengers that from today 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Machu Picchu rules and regulations </title>
      <link>https://www.guidetomachupicchu.com/blogs/2020-01-05-machu-picchu-rules-and-regulations/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2020 23:49:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.guidetomachupicchu.com/blogs/2020-01-05-machu-picchu-rules-and-regulations/</guid>
      <description>Machu Picchu has several rules in place to protect the site from potential damage These rules are being applied with more rigor every year and are important to respect There are some ticket regulations and limitations as well as rules of conduct for Machu Picchu Machu Picchu Guards are present to make sure these rules are being respected These rules and regulations can and have changed without prior notice  Rules of entrance When visiting unique sites, that are part of the legacy of humankind, it is logical that these places have to be protected in order for man to be able to enjoy this legacy in centuries to come.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Problems with paying for Machu Picchu tickets online?</title>
      <link>https://www.guidetomachupicchu.com/questions/2019-12-29-problems-with-paying-for-machu-picchu-tickets-online/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 15:07:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.guidetomachupicchu.com/questions/2019-12-29-problems-with-paying-for-machu-picchu-tickets-online/</guid>
      <description>As every year the official government website (https://www.machupicchu.gob.pe/inicio) is running behind on the sale of Machu Picchu tickets for 2020. At this time (December 2019) the only tickets available online are till January 5, 2020. All other Machu Picchu tickets for 2020 will not be available online till January 2. It seems prices will remain the same as in 2019.
Related Content : Details on Machu Picchu entrance tickets for 2020  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Can I do a one day trip from Cusco to Machu Picchu?</title>
      <link>https://www.guidetomachupicchu.com/questions/2019-12-28-can-i-do-a-one-day-trip-from-cusco-to-machu-picchu/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 15:05:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.guidetomachupicchu.com/questions/2019-12-28-can-i-do-a-one-day-trip-from-cusco-to-machu-picchu/</guid>
      <description>Logistically this is not a problem but keep in mind that it will be a long day (5.00am departure Cusco / 9.00pm arrival). A one day trip also limits your chances on climbing Huayna Picchu as this can only be done in the morning. This is why a two day trip is recommended if time allows.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What about bringing luggage on Peru Rail?</title>
      <link>https://www.guidetomachupicchu.com/questions/2019-12-28-what-about-bringing-luggage-on-peru-rail/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 15:05:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.guidetomachupicchu.com/questions/2019-12-28-what-about-bringing-luggage-on-peru-rail/</guid>
      <description>Peru Rail as well as the other train company Inca Rail more or less manage the same luggage limitations. Officially this is for 5kg (12lbs) per person in a small hand luggage kind of bag. This is not imposed too strictly but as storage space on the trains is limited it is best to try to respect the norm as much as possible.
Related Content : Read More Details on luggage limitations for trains  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Taking a baby up Huayna Picchu (Machu Picchu)?</title>
      <link>https://www.guidetomachupicchu.com/questions/2019-12-28-taking-a-baby-up-huayna-picchu-machu-picchu/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 15:04:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.guidetomachupicchu.com/questions/2019-12-28-taking-a-baby-up-huayna-picchu-machu-picchu/</guid>
      <description>Good question; I personally have been to Machu Picchu with my 1 year old daughter and it was an interesting experience. She obviously did not see much of Machu Picchu as she slept in the baby carrier (the ones you can strap to yourself, which was very handy) but if you have to do all ups and downs, steps and stairs by yourself you will be exhausted by the end of the day.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Overall cost Of traveling to Peru &amp; MP?</title>
      <link>https://www.guidetomachupicchu.com/questions/2019-12-28-overall-cost-of-traveling-to-peru-mp/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 14:57:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.guidetomachupicchu.com/questions/2019-12-28-overall-cost-of-traveling-to-peru-mp/</guid>
      <description>As with many of the new world wonders, traveling to Machu Picchu comes at a cost. The actual costs can of course be influenced by the choices of the individual traveler but for most people the basic costs will include; entrance tickets (around US$60pp), train tickets (from US$120pp for the return trip) and buses to and from the entrance (US$24pp). Apart from this you need to get to and from the train station, spend the night in a hotel somewhere and of course need some food and water.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Machu Picchu - plan own itinerary or book a travel package</title>
      <link>https://www.guidetomachupicchu.com/questions/2019-12-28-machu-picchu-plan-own-itinerary-or-book-a-travel-package/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 14:57:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.guidetomachupicchu.com/questions/2019-12-28-machu-picchu-plan-own-itinerary-or-book-a-travel-package/</guid>
      <description>Even though a trip to Peru and Machu Picchu can these days easily be planned for yourself using the internet, many people still book a complete vacation package when visiting Peru and/or Machu Picchu; why? Well the main reason is time; for those with limited time for this trip booking with a travel agency may be the way to go as this will allow you to maximize your time at each destination and rely on the inside knowledge of the agency to make the itinerary as efficient as possible taking into consideration the climate, altitude and other factors.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Machu Picchu in December?</title>
      <link>https://www.guidetomachupicchu.com/questions/2019-12-28-machu-picchu-in-december/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 14:56:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.guidetomachupicchu.com/questions/2019-12-28-machu-picchu-in-december/</guid>
      <description>December in general is a great month to come to Peru as the festivities this time of the year make traveling in December a little bit more colorful. Weather-wise December is the start of the rainy season in Peru but this does not mean that it rains every day or all day. In general the rain is not that prevalent in December yet and temperatures are on the rise as this is also the start of the summer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lima to Machu Picchu, how to get there?</title>
      <link>https://www.guidetomachupicchu.com/questions/2019-12-28-lima-to-machu-picchu/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 14:55:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.guidetomachupicchu.com/questions/2019-12-28-lima-to-machu-picchu/</guid>
      <description>Most people coming from abroad visiting Machu Picchu have to arrive to Lima first. Lima is Peru’s capital and the main international airport. Peru is a large country so from Lima one has to travel to Cusco (1.5hrs flying or 24hrs bussing) and from here set course for Machu Picchu. From Cusco it is another 100km which can be done with a combination of cars and trains. To travel from Lima to Machu Picchu one should foresee a full day of traveling.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Huayna (Wayna) Picchu or Machu Picchu Mountain?</title>
      <link>https://www.guidetomachupicchu.com/questions/2019-12-28-huayna-wayna-picchu-or-machu-picchu-mountain/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 14:55:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.guidetomachupicchu.com/questions/2019-12-28-huayna-wayna-picchu-or-machu-picchu-mountain/</guid>
      <description>Between these two optional mountains one can climb when in Machu Picchu, it is obvious that Huayna Picchu is the most important one and since the number of visitors have been limited almost became a separate bucket list destination next to Machu Picchu itself. The main reason, apart from the obvious spectacular views is the fact that on top of this mountain the temple of the Moon can be found as well as some “impossible” terraces.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Drone Usage at Machu Picchu?</title>
      <link>https://www.guidetomachupicchu.com/questions/2019-12-28-drone-usage-at-machu-picchu/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 14:52:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.guidetomachupicchu.com/questions/2019-12-28-drone-usage-at-machu-picchu/</guid>
      <description>Drones are not allowed at Machu Picchu (officially at any of the Inca sites) under the law that protects the park from overflights of helicopters as well. Permits can be obtained for professional filming of Machu Picchu (very expensive and complicated but possible) but permits for drones are never given out. Earlier this year there was a visitor that filmed Machu Picchu with a drone and he was tracked down to appear in court.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cell Phone Coverage At MP?</title>
      <link>https://www.guidetomachupicchu.com/questions/2019-12-28-cell-phone-coverage-at-mp/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 14:51:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.guidetomachupicchu.com/questions/2019-12-28-cell-phone-coverage-at-mp/</guid>
      <description>The whole site of Machu Picchu has cell phone coverage as well as mobile internet most of the time. The mobile internet can be affected at times due to the location and weather conditions but in general is available. Internet speed may not always be very good. The Inca Trail only has cell phone coverage on certain points and very little mobile internet access till the last day when you get closer to Machu Picchu.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Buying the bus ticket to Machu Picchu</title>
      <link>https://www.guidetomachupicchu.com/questions/2019-12-28-buying-the-bus-ticket-to-machu-picchu/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 14:51:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.guidetomachupicchu.com/questions/2019-12-28-buying-the-bus-ticket-to-machu-picchu/</guid>
      <description>Bus tickets to Machu Picchu can be purchased online (http://consettur.com/reservas/) or at the Consettur offices in Cusco or Aguas Calientes. The ones in Aguas Calientes are located just around the corner from the bus stop and prices are the same whether you purchase online or in person. For foreign visitors the price is US$24 for the return ticket.
Related Content : Read More Details on buses to Machu Picchu  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Altitude Sickness - How Worried Should I Be??? </title>
      <link>https://www.guidetomachupicchu.com/questions/2019-12-28-altitude-sickness-how-worried-should-i-be/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 14:50:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.guidetomachupicchu.com/questions/2019-12-28-altitude-sickness-how-worried-should-i-be/</guid>
      <description>I am glad to inform that for Machu Picchu the altitude is not an issue for most people. As Machu Picchu is located almost 3,500ft lower than Cusco on an altitude of 7,900ft, well under the 10,000ft level on which most people start feeling the altitude. With an altitude of about 7,900ft it is unlikely that the altitude will be an issue during your Machu Picchu visit. For the4 day Inca Trail hike to Machu Picchu the altitude is a factor to take into consideration as you will be coming over passes will over 13,000ft.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tips for Machu Picchu?</title>
      <link>https://www.guidetomachupicchu.com/questions/2019-12-28-tips-for-machu-picchu/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 14:18:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.guidetomachupicchu.com/questions/2019-12-28-tips-for-machu-picchu/</guid>
      <description>Some tips for Machu Picchu; officially one cannot take food into Machu Picchu. Small sandwiches for an improvised picnic on the guardsman house area are tolerated. Make sure that your walking stick has a rubber protection for the tip, if not this will not be allowed. Umbrellas are often not tolerated. There are no bathrooms on the site; only at the entrance. Only the tickets with Huayna Picchu or Montaña allow for a re-entrance to use the bathrooms.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aguas Calientes or Machu Picchu Pueblo?</title>
      <link>https://www.guidetomachupicchu.com/blogs/2019-12-31-aguas-calientes-or-machu-picchu-pueblo/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2019 02:34:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.guidetomachupicchu.com/blogs/2019-12-31-aguas-calientes-or-machu-picchu-pueblo/</guid>
      <description>Machu Picchu Pueblo is the new name of Aguas Calientes Aguas Calientes translates into Warm Waters and refers to the local thermal springs The town can only be accessed on foot or by trainIt is here that the trains to Machu Picchu arrive and the buses depart Aguas Calientes has a large variety of hotels and restaurants  Aguas Calientes is the old name of the town that is located in the valley down from the famous Inca site of Machu Picchu.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A brief History of Machu Picchu</title>
      <link>https://www.guidetomachupicchu.com/blogs/2019-12-31-a-brief-history-of-machu-picchu/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2019 02:28:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.guidetomachupicchu.com/blogs/2019-12-31-a-brief-history-of-machu-picchu/</guid>
      <description>Machu Picchu was built around 1450 and abandoned around 1533 The Spanish Conquistadors never made it to Machu Picchu It was forgotten for almost 450 years till it was rediscovered in the early 1900’s In 1911 Hiram Bingham, a Yale Explorer officially rediscovered the site Machu Picchu is by far South America’s nr. 1 archeological site  Inca Times Being the number one archeological site of South America one cannot visit Machu Picchu without a little background information.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Should I get a guide?</title>
      <link>https://www.guidetomachupicchu.com/questions/2019-12-29-should-i-get-a-guide/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2019 21:17:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.guidetomachupicchu.com/questions/2019-12-29-should-i-get-a-guide/</guid>
      <description>Good Question; Officially; Yes you need a guide for a first time Machu Picchu visit. Unofficially; the rule is in place but is not applied and does not seem to be applied in the near future. Secondly, deciding on a guide or not is also something that depends from person to person. Some people enjoy their visit more and some less with a guide so this is very personally. As all Machu Picchu visits are now limited to a fixed route all visits will have more or less the same order and therefore a guide perhaps less necessary.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Do I need my passport to enter Machu Picchu</title>
      <link>https://www.guidetomachupicchu.com/questions/2019-12-29-do-i-need-my-passport-to-enter-machu-picchu/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2019 21:13:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.guidetomachupicchu.com/questions/2019-12-29-do-i-need-my-passport-to-enter-machu-picchu/</guid>
      <description>Yes; upon entering Machu Picchu you will be asked for official proof of identification. This can be with a local ID card for Peruvians and the surrounding countries but for foreigners this will always be with the international passport. Keep in mind that all tickets have to be purchased with a passport number and this has to match the one provided upon entering. If you would change passports between the time you purchase the ticket and the time of travel, you must inform the INC of this change; preferably with at copy of the old and the new passport.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Are there places to eat in Machu Picchu?</title>
      <link>https://www.guidetomachupicchu.com/questions/2019-12-29-are-there-places-to-eat-in-machu-picchu/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2019 21:07:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.guidetomachupicchu.com/questions/2019-12-29-are-there-places-to-eat-in-machu-picchu/</guid>
      <description>At Machu Picchu itself there are two options to eat something but both of these are located just outside the entrance of the site. The first is the Tinkuy Buffet Restaurant located next to the Sanctuary Lodge Hotel and the second is a small snack bar located on the right hand side of the entrance. Both are relatively pricey and officially it is forbidden to take food into the site itself.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Are the myths about secret chambers and escape routes true?</title>
      <link>https://www.guidetomachupicchu.com/questions/2019-12-29-are-the-myths-about-secret-chambers-and-escape-routes-true/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2019 21:03:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.guidetomachupicchu.com/questions/2019-12-29-are-the-myths-about-secret-chambers-and-escape-routes-true/</guid>
      <description>It is true that Machu Picchu has a lot of secrets and that some things we will never understand completely but this is as far as the mystery would go. Machu Picchu has been searched and scanned from top to bottom and back and scientists are pretty certain there will not be any new secret locations appear unless they would be hidden in the large rocks. The escape route you may have heard about probably refer to a path that runs next to Huayna Picchu Mountain but this runs into a dead end.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New rules for Machu Picchu in 2017, are some being enforced in 2020?</title>
      <link>https://www.guidetomachupicchu.com/questions/2019-12-28-new-rules-for-machu-picchu-in-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2019 03:24:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.guidetomachupicchu.com/questions/2019-12-28-new-rules-for-machu-picchu-in-2017/</guid>
      <description>In 2017 the INC, governing body for Machu Picchu started implementing new rules and regulations for visitors to Machu Picchu. The aim for these are to better manage the number of visitors, waiting times and general management. These rules took some time to implement and many of these are only being enforced from 2020 onward.
Related Content : Details on Machu Picchu entrance tickets for 2020  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hiking to Machu Picchu</title>
      <link>https://www.guidetomachupicchu.com/blogs/2019-12-30-hiking-to-machu-picchu/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2019 03:10:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.guidetomachupicchu.com/blogs/2019-12-30-hiking-to-machu-picchu/</guid>
      <description>Machu Picchu can only be reached by train or on foot On foot there are several options; the Inca Trail or Salkantay Hike The Inca Trail provides a long (4 days) and short (2 days) version The Inca Trail also visits other Inca sites that can only be reached via these trails The Inca Trails arrive through the Sun Gate and the Salkanty via Aguas Calientes  Hikes to Machu Picchu The train is by far the easiest way to get to Machu Picchu but hiking is without doubt the most beautiful.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hiking Machu Picchu Mountain </title>
      <link>https://www.guidetomachupicchu.com/blogs/2019-12-30-hiking-machu-picchu-mountain/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2019 03:06:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.guidetomachupicchu.com/blogs/2019-12-30-hiking-machu-picchu-mountain/</guid>
      <description>Machu Picchu Mountain is the best alternative for those we cannot hike Huayna Picchu Machu Picchu Mountain is located on the South side of Machu Picchu The top is located at a breathtaking 10,120ft (3,085m) above sea level The hike takes about 2 hours up and 1 hour to come back down The hike is best done on the start of your Machu Picchu visit due to its location  In recent years Huayna Picchu Mountain has gained a lot of attraction and has become so popular that the amount of visitors had to be limited in order to protect this part of Machu Picchu.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to travel to Machu Picchu</title>
      <link>https://www.guidetomachupicchu.com/blogs/2019-12-29-how-to-travel-to-machu-picchu/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Dec 2019 12:13:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.guidetomachupicchu.com/blogs/2019-12-29-how-to-travel-to-machu-picchu/</guid>
      <description>Machu Picchu is located in the Cusco region in South Peru Cusco is the closest airport and is located at about 100km from Machu Picchu In order to travel from Cusco to Machu Picchu one will pass through the Sacred Valley Machu Picchu can be visited in two ways; by train or on foot For the train there are three stations, 2 companies with three levels of trains Hiking to Machu Picchu can be done via the original 4 or 1 day Inca Trails or the 5 day Salkantay Trail  Visiting Machu Picchu, unless you are lucky enough to live in Peru, takes some time and effort but the rewards are undeniably unique and breathtaking.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hiking Huayna Picchu</title>
      <link>https://www.guidetomachupicchu.com/blogs/2019-12-29-hiking-huayna-picchu/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Dec 2019 11:59:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.guidetomachupicchu.com/blogs/2019-12-29-hiking-huayna-picchu/</guid>
      <description>Huayna Picchu Mountain is the famous mountain on the northern end of Machu Picchu The hike is limited in number of visitors; 400 people daily divided into two groups Two time windows for this hike; 7.00am and 10.00am (200 visitors per time window) Tickets for Huayna Picchu sell out for most day and months in advance The cost for the Machu Picchu and Huayna Picchu ticket is 200 Soles (US$62) per person  Huayna Picchu is the name given to the granite mountain that towers over Machu Picchu on the northern end of the site, carved on all ends by the Vilcanote River running around it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Machu Picchu Weather </title>
      <link>https://www.guidetomachupicchu.com/blogs/2019-12-29-machu-picchu-weather/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Dec 2019 11:54:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.guidetomachupicchu.com/blogs/2019-12-29-machu-picchu-weather/</guid>
      <description>Machu Picchu has two seasons; the dry and the rainy season December is the start of the rainy season April is the start of the dry season Every year in March / April the dry season starts Day temperatures throughout the year are around 72°F (22°C) Chances of clouds and rain are higher in the mornings  Generally speaking, Machu Picchu weather is relatively warm during the daytime and tends to cool off at night.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Luggage Limitations trains to Machu Picchu</title>
      <link>https://www.guidetomachupicchu.com/blogs/2019-12-29-luggage-limitations-trains-to-machu-picchu/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Dec 2019 11:52:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.guidetomachupicchu.com/blogs/2019-12-29-luggage-limitations-trains-to-machu-picchu/</guid>
      <description>Most visitors to Machu Picchu get there by train Trains to Machu Picchu have limited luggage storage Official luggage allowance for the trains are; a maximum weight limit of 5.0 kg/11 Unofficially weight limits do not matter but oversized luggage cannot be taken on board It is recommended to only take the luggage you need to Machu Picchu and leave the rest in storage  With on average 2,000 people visiting Machu Picchu per day; 90% of these coming by train and 50% spending at least one night in Aguas Calientes you can imagine the amount of luggage that goes back and forth every day.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Machu Picchu entrance tickets 2020 - Latest Updates </title>
      <link>https://www.guidetomachupicchu.com/blogs/2019-12-29-machu-picchu-entrance-tickets-2020-latest-updates/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Dec 2019 11:41:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.guidetomachupicchu.com/blogs/2019-12-29-machu-picchu-entrance-tickets-2020-latest-updates/</guid>
      <description>Machu Picchu tickets for 2020 will be on sale from January 2, 2020 onward Prices will remain the same as in 2019 Tickets are sold with fixed entrance times, allowing four hours on site Visitors have to follow the mandatory circuits and routes that have been put in place Even though stated in the regulations, a guide for first time visits is not yet obligatory for 2020  As every year there are some new rules and regulations that are being put in place to protect Machu Picchu from the growing number of visitors.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Buses to Machu Picchu</title>
      <link>https://www.guidetomachupicchu.com/blogs/2019-12-29-buses-to-machu-picchu/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Dec 2019 04:49:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.guidetomachupicchu.com/blogs/2019-12-29-buses-to-machu-picchu/</guid>
      <description>Trains arrive to Aguas Calientes Station and from here it is another 30 minutes in bus** There is only one bus company providing buses to Machu Picchu** Tickets can be purchased in advance or the day itself** You can only embark the buses one hour prior to the entrance time stated on your ticket** Bus lines work with a first come, first serve system** Prices are US$24 per foreign adult for the return ticket**  Let’s say you made it to Lima, flew to Cusco and traveled by train or on foot to Aguas Calientes, now you can embark on the final part of the experience it is getting to Machu Picchu; the bus (unless you feel like a 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Trains to Machu Picchu</title>
      <link>https://www.guidetomachupicchu.com/blogs/2019-12-29-trains-to-machu-picchu/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Dec 2019 04:46:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.guidetomachupicchu.com/blogs/2019-12-29-trains-to-machu-picchu/</guid>
      <description>Trains are the most popular mode of transport to Machu Picchu There are three stations that operate trains to Machu Picchu; Cusco, Poroy and Ollantaytambo Two train companies; PeruRail and Inca Rail offer train services to Machu Picchu Both companies have three different levels of train; Economy, Superior and Deluxe PeruRail (Poroy and Ollantaytambo); Expedition, Vistadome and Hiram Bingham Service Inca Rail (Cusco, Poroy and Ollantaytambo); Voyager, 360° and First Class Service Both companies offer multiple train departure times for both ways  Stations to Machu Picchu Most people visit Machu Picchu by train as this is the quickest way to get to Machu Picchu.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact Us</title>
      <link>https://www.guidetomachupicchu.com/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Feb 2018 17:01:34 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.guidetomachupicchu.com/contact/</guid>
      <description>Contact Us or Ask us a Question Name  Email  We&amp;rsquo;ll never share your email with anyone else.  Your Message or Question:   Submit</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Restaurants</title>
      <link>https://www.guidetomachupicchu.com/restaurants/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Feb 2018 17:01:34 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.guidetomachupicchu.com/restaurants/</guid>
      <description>Restaurants </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Search</title>
      <link>https://www.guidetomachupicchu.com/search/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Jul 2017 19:57:50 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.guidetomachupicchu.com/search/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About Us</title>
      <link>https://www.guidetomachupicchu.com/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.guidetomachupicchu.com/about/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to Guide to Machu Picchu. Our mission is providing Machu Picchu visitors with a place of reference for the latest updates and news on Peru’s top destination;
Machu Picchu. Located high up in the Andes Mountains, Machu Picchu may have been discovered for more than a century but getting there may still be a bit of an overwhelming undertaking. So, if you are looking to travel to Machu Picchu and want to stay up to date with the latest news, best routes and practical tips, you have come to the right page.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>