<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>machu picchu hiking on Your Guide to Machu Picchu</title>
    <link>https://www.guidetomachupicchu.com/tags/machu-picchu-hiking/</link>
    <description>Recent content in machu picchu hiking on Your Guide to Machu Picchu</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2020 23:30:52 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.guidetomachupicchu.com/tags/machu-picchu-hiking/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Machu Picchu Altitude</title>
      <link>https://www.guidetomachupicchu.com/blogs/2020-01-07-machu-picchu-altitude/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2020 23:30:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.guidetomachupicchu.com/blogs/2020-01-07-machu-picchu-altitude/</guid>
      <description>Machu Picchu is located on 7,350ft, much lower than Cusco Most visitors have little or no issues with the altitude in Machu Picchu The lower altitude and proximity to the jungle makes the Machu Picchu climate warmer and more humid The lower altitude is the reason some visitors prefer first to visit machu Picchu and then Cusco Machu Picchu is located about 100km (3 hours) from Cusco  Cusco is infamous for its high altitude (almost 12,000ft (3,500m) and the chances of getting altitude sickness.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hiking to Machu Picchu</title>
      <link>https://www.guidetomachupicchu.com/blogs/2019-12-30-hiking-to-machu-picchu/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2019 03:10:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.guidetomachupicchu.com/blogs/2019-12-30-hiking-to-machu-picchu/</guid>
      <description>Machu Picchu can only be reached by train or on foot On foot there are several options; the Inca Trail or Salkantay Hike The Inca Trail provides a long (4 days) and short (2 days) version The Inca Trail also visits other Inca sites that can only be reached via these trails The Inca Trails arrive through the Sun Gate and the Salkanty via Aguas Calientes  Hikes to Machu Picchu The train is by far the easiest way to get to Machu Picchu but hiking is without doubt the most beautiful.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hiking Machu Picchu Mountain </title>
      <link>https://www.guidetomachupicchu.com/blogs/2019-12-30-hiking-machu-picchu-mountain/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2019 03:06:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.guidetomachupicchu.com/blogs/2019-12-30-hiking-machu-picchu-mountain/</guid>
      <description>Machu Picchu Mountain is the best alternative for those we cannot hike Huayna Picchu Machu Picchu Mountain is located on the South side of Machu Picchu The top is located at a breathtaking 10,120ft (3,085m) above sea level The hike takes about 2 hours up and 1 hour to come back down The hike is best done on the start of your Machu Picchu visit due to its location  In recent years Huayna Picchu Mountain has gained a lot of attraction and has become so popular that the amount of visitors had to be limited in order to protect this part of Machu Picchu.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hiking Huayna Picchu</title>
      <link>https://www.guidetomachupicchu.com/blogs/2019-12-29-hiking-huayna-picchu/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Dec 2019 11:59:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.guidetomachupicchu.com/blogs/2019-12-29-hiking-huayna-picchu/</guid>
      <description>Huayna Picchu Mountain is the famous mountain on the northern end of Machu Picchu The hike is limited in number of visitors; 400 people daily divided into two groups Two time windows for this hike; 7.00am and 10.00am (200 visitors per time window) Tickets for Huayna Picchu sell out for most day and months in advance The cost for the Machu Picchu and Huayna Picchu ticket is 200 Soles (US$62) per person  Huayna Picchu is the name given to the granite mountain that towers over Machu Picchu on the northern end of the site, carved on all ends by the Vilcanote River running around it.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>