<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>buses to machu picchu on Your Guide to Machu Picchu</title>
    <link>https://www.guidetomachupicchu.com/tags/buses-to-machu-picchu/</link>
    <description>Recent content in buses to machu picchu on Your Guide to Machu Picchu</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2020 04:30:20 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.guidetomachupicchu.com/tags/buses-to-machu-picchu/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Traveling to Machu Picchu; 10 practical tips for visitors</title>
      <link>https://www.guidetomachupicchu.com/blogs/2020-01-09-traveling-to-machu-picchu-10-practical-tips-for-visitors/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2020 04:30:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.guidetomachupicchu.com/blogs/2020-01-09-traveling-to-machu-picchu-10-practical-tips-for-visitors/</guid>
      <description>Machu Picchu Visitor Tips Machu Picchu is a unique and adventurous destination but is perhaps not as easy to get to as some of the other bucket list destinations that often get listed. For the Colosseum you fly to Rome and the rest is all pretty straight forward. For Christ the Redeemer you fly to Rio and can even take a taxi there. For Machu Picchu this is not that simple making that one would need at least two (preferably more) days in Peru to see Machu Picchu.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aguas Calientes or Machu Picchu Pueblo?</title>
      <link>https://www.guidetomachupicchu.com/blogs/2019-12-31-aguas-calientes-or-machu-picchu-pueblo/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2019 02:34:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.guidetomachupicchu.com/blogs/2019-12-31-aguas-calientes-or-machu-picchu-pueblo/</guid>
      <description>Machu Picchu Pueblo is the new name of Aguas Calientes Aguas Calientes translates into Warm Waters and refers to the local thermal springs The town can only be accessed on foot or by trainIt is here that the trains to Machu Picchu arrive and the buses depart Aguas Calientes has a large variety of hotels and restaurants  Aguas Calientes is the old name of the town that is located in the valley down from the famous Inca site of Machu Picchu.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>