<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>weather on Your Guide to Machu Picchu</title>
    <link>https://www.guidetomachupicchu.com/tags/weather/</link>
    <description>Recent content in weather on Your Guide to Machu Picchu</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2020 20:03:49 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.guidetomachupicchu.com/tags/weather/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Best time of the year to visit Machu Picchu</title>
      <link>https://www.guidetomachupicchu.com/blogs/2020-01-12-best-time-of-the-year-to-visit-machu-picchu/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2020 20:03:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.guidetomachupicchu.com/blogs/2020-01-12-best-time-of-the-year-to-visit-machu-picchu/</guid>
      <description>Best time to visit Machu Picchu is in the dry season June, July and August busiest months March and November, transition months Best time of the year; April, May, September and October  Machu Picchu can without issues be visited all year round and open 365 days in the year. This being said, being an outdoors location, Machu Picchu is subject to the local weather conditions. As you will read almost anywhere; the best time of the year to visit Machu Picchu is the dry season.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Machu Picchu in December?</title>
      <link>https://www.guidetomachupicchu.com/questions/2019-12-28-machu-picchu-in-december/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 14:56:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.guidetomachupicchu.com/questions/2019-12-28-machu-picchu-in-december/</guid>
      <description>December in general is a great month to come to Peru as the festivities this time of the year make traveling in December a little bit more colorful. Weather-wise December is the start of the rainy season in Peru but this does not mean that it rains every day or all day. In general the rain is not that prevalent in December yet and temperatures are on the rise as this is also the start of the summer.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>