<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>machu picchu weather on Your Guide to Machu Picchu</title>
    <link>https://www.guidetomachupicchu.com/tags/machu-picchu-weather/</link>
    <description>Recent content in machu picchu weather on Your Guide to Machu Picchu</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2020 20:23:55 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.guidetomachupicchu.com/tags/machu-picchu-weather/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>What are the temperatures like at Machu Picchu?</title>
      <link>https://www.guidetomachupicchu.com/questions/2020-01-12-what-are-the-temperatures-like-at-machu-picchu/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2020 20:23:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.guidetomachupicchu.com/questions/2020-01-12-what-are-the-temperatures-like-at-machu-picchu/</guid>
      <description>Machu Picchu weather most of the time is pleasantly warm during the day. Night times do not get really cold either except for some nights in July and August. Temperatures in Machu Picchu and Aguas Calientes range between 50 and 75 degrees Fahrenheit (12 and 24 degrees Celsius). More so than temperature, weather at Machu Picchu is distinguished more by its dry season and wet season. Humidity levels are always high making sensational temperature often higher than the real ones.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Machu Picchu Altitude</title>
      <link>https://www.guidetomachupicchu.com/blogs/2020-01-07-machu-picchu-altitude/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2020 23:30:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.guidetomachupicchu.com/blogs/2020-01-07-machu-picchu-altitude/</guid>
      <description>Machu Picchu is located on 7,350ft, much lower than Cusco Most visitors have little or no issues with the altitude in Machu Picchu The lower altitude and proximity to the jungle makes the Machu Picchu climate warmer and more humid The lower altitude is the reason some visitors prefer first to visit machu Picchu and then Cusco Machu Picchu is located about 100km (3 hours) from Cusco  Cusco is infamous for its high altitude (almost 12,000ft (3,500m) and the chances of getting altitude sickness.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Machu Picchu Weather </title>
      <link>https://www.guidetomachupicchu.com/blogs/2019-12-29-machu-picchu-weather/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Dec 2019 11:54:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.guidetomachupicchu.com/blogs/2019-12-29-machu-picchu-weather/</guid>
      <description>Machu Picchu has two seasons; the dry and the rainy season December is the start of the rainy season April is the start of the dry season Every year in March / April the dry season starts Day temperatures throughout the year are around 72°F (22°C) Chances of clouds and rain are higher in the mornings  Generally speaking, Machu Picchu weather is relatively warm during the daytime and tends to cool off at night.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>