<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>trains to machu picchu on Your Guide to Machu Picchu</title>
    <link>https://www.guidetomachupicchu.com/tags/trains-to-machu-picchu/</link>
    <description>Recent content in trains to machu picchu on Your Guide to Machu Picchu</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2020 18:33:47 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.guidetomachupicchu.com/tags/trains-to-machu-picchu/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Is Inca Rail cheaper than Peru Rail?</title>
      <link>https://www.guidetomachupicchu.com/questions/2020-01-10-is-inca-rail-cheaper-than-peru-rail/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2020 18:33:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.guidetomachupicchu.com/questions/2020-01-10-is-inca-rail-cheaper-than-peru-rail/</guid>
      <description>Inca Rail used to be quite some cheaper than Peru Rail but nowadays the difference is only felt in the deluxe version of the train; the First Class Train. The starting level, Voyager you can book for US$59 to US$72 one way and the Superior 360° Train from US$77 to US$86 one way. The difference with similar levels with Peru Rail is only a couple of Dollars. The First Class Train goes at US$200 one way.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How much does the Train to Machu Picchu cost?</title>
      <link>https://www.guidetomachupicchu.com/questions/2020-01-10-how-much-does-the-train-to-machu-picchu-cost/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2020 18:32:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.guidetomachupicchu.com/questions/2020-01-10-how-much-does-the-train-to-machu-picchu-cost/</guid>
      <description>Peru Rail has three train types to Machu Picchu. The Expedition Train costs between US$54 and US$ 68 one way and the Vistadome between US$77 to US$95 one way. Prices fluctuate depending on the departure times and train stations. The upgrade to the Hiram Bingham is a little steep at US$495 one way but you get a luxury train, meals and drinks in return.
https://www.perurail.com/
Related Content : Details on trains to Machu Picchu  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Traveling to Machu Picchu; 10 practical tips for visitors</title>
      <link>https://www.guidetomachupicchu.com/blogs/2020-01-09-traveling-to-machu-picchu-10-practical-tips-for-visitors/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2020 04:30:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.guidetomachupicchu.com/blogs/2020-01-09-traveling-to-machu-picchu-10-practical-tips-for-visitors/</guid>
      <description>Machu Picchu Visitor Tips Machu Picchu is a unique and adventurous destination but is perhaps not as easy to get to as some of the other bucket list destinations that often get listed. For the Colosseum you fly to Rome and the rest is all pretty straight forward. For Christ the Redeemer you fly to Rio and can even take a taxi there. For Machu Picchu this is not that simple making that one would need at least two (preferably more) days in Peru to see Machu Picchu.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LATEST UPDATE; Train services to Machu Picchu reinstated</title>
      <link>https://www.guidetomachupicchu.com/blogs/2020-01-06-latest-update-train-services-to-machu-picchu-reinstated/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2020 14:37:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.guidetomachupicchu.com/blogs/2020-01-06-latest-update-train-services-to-machu-picchu-reinstated/</guid>
      <description>Train services to Machu Picchu have been reinstated according the normal schedule All visitors can complete their Machu Picchu visit as planned Water levels of the Vilcanota River have returned to normal levels The train companies remain vigilant of the situation January and February are the months with most rain in the Machu Picchu region  January 6, 2020 This morning Ferrocarril Transandino S.A, the company that runs the train tracks to Machu Picchu, informed the train companies Peru Rail and Inca Rail they can resume train services to and from Machu Picchu according to the normal schedule and frequencies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Latest Update - Machu Picchu inaccessible by train</title>
      <link>https://www.guidetomachupicchu.com/blogs/2020-01-06-latest-update-machu-picchu-inaccessible/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2020 02:44:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.guidetomachupicchu.com/blogs/2020-01-06-latest-update-machu-picchu-inaccessible/</guid>
      <description>TRAIN SERVICES TO MACHU PICCHU HAVE RESUMED
Related Content : TRAIN SERVICES TO MACHU PICCHU HAVE RESUMED  January 6, 2020 - Yesterday a press release was emitted by Ferrocarril Transandino S.A, the company that runs the train tracks to Machu Picchu, that till further notice there would not be any trains allowed to travel to Machu Picchu. This is because the rising waters of the Vilcanota (Urubamba) River are threatening the train tracks that run besides them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Latest News; Machu Picchu Temporarily Not accessible</title>
      <link>https://www.guidetomachupicchu.com/blogs/2020-01-06-latest-new-machu-picchu-temporarily-not-accessible/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2020 00:44:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.guidetomachupicchu.com/blogs/2020-01-06-latest-new-machu-picchu-temporarily-not-accessible/</guid>
      <description>TRAIN SERVICES TO MACHU PICCHU HAVE RESUMED
Related Content : TRAIN SERVICES TO MACHU PICCHU HAVE RESUMED   Machu Picchu temporarily not accessible by train Not clear how hikes to Machu Picchu will be affected Measure because of increased water level of Vilcanota River Start of the rainy season- measure in place till water levels decrease  Cusco; January 5, 2020 - The Ferrocarril Transandino S.A., the company that operates the train tracks between Cusco and Machu Picchu (Aguas Calientes) has released a statement today informing all passengers that from today 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aguas Calientes or Machu Picchu Pueblo?</title>
      <link>https://www.guidetomachupicchu.com/blogs/2019-12-31-aguas-calientes-or-machu-picchu-pueblo/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2019 02:34:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.guidetomachupicchu.com/blogs/2019-12-31-aguas-calientes-or-machu-picchu-pueblo/</guid>
      <description>Machu Picchu Pueblo is the new name of Aguas Calientes Aguas Calientes translates into Warm Waters and refers to the local thermal springs The town can only be accessed on foot or by trainIt is here that the trains to Machu Picchu arrive and the buses depart Aguas Calientes has a large variety of hotels and restaurants  Aguas Calientes is the old name of the town that is located in the valley down from the famous Inca site of Machu Picchu.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Trains to Machu Picchu</title>
      <link>https://www.guidetomachupicchu.com/blogs/2019-12-29-trains-to-machu-picchu/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Dec 2019 04:46:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.guidetomachupicchu.com/blogs/2019-12-29-trains-to-machu-picchu/</guid>
      <description>Trains are the most popular mode of transport to Machu Picchu There are three stations that operate trains to Machu Picchu; Cusco, Poroy and Ollantaytambo Two train companies; PeruRail and Inca Rail offer train services to Machu Picchu Both companies have three different levels of train; Economy, Superior and Deluxe PeruRail (Poroy and Ollantaytambo); Expedition, Vistadome and Hiram Bingham Service Inca Rail (Cusco, Poroy and Ollantaytambo); Voyager, 360° and First Class Service Both companies offer multiple train departure times for both ways  Stations to Machu Picchu Most people visit Machu Picchu by train as this is the quickest way to get to Machu Picchu.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>