<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Huayna Picchu on Your Guide to Machu Picchu</title>
    <link>https://www.guidetomachupicchu.com/tags/huayna-picchu/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Huayna Picchu on Your Guide to Machu Picchu</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 15:04:50 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.guidetomachupicchu.com/tags/huayna-picchu/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Taking a baby up Huayna Picchu (Machu Picchu)?</title>
      <link>https://www.guidetomachupicchu.com/questions/2019-12-28-taking-a-baby-up-huayna-picchu-machu-picchu/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 15:04:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.guidetomachupicchu.com/questions/2019-12-28-taking-a-baby-up-huayna-picchu-machu-picchu/</guid>
      <description>Good question; I personally have been to Machu Picchu with my 1 year old daughter and it was an interesting experience. She obviously did not see much of Machu Picchu as she slept in the baby carrier (the ones you can strap to yourself, which was very handy) but if you have to do all ups and downs, steps and stairs by yourself you will be exhausted by the end of the day.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Huayna (Wayna) Picchu or Machu Picchu Mountain?</title>
      <link>https://www.guidetomachupicchu.com/questions/2019-12-28-huayna-wayna-picchu-or-machu-picchu-mountain/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 14:55:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.guidetomachupicchu.com/questions/2019-12-28-huayna-wayna-picchu-or-machu-picchu-mountain/</guid>
      <description>Between these two optional mountains one can climb when in Machu Picchu, it is obvious that Huayna Picchu is the most important one and since the number of visitors have been limited almost became a separate bucket list destination next to Machu Picchu itself. The main reason, apart from the obvious spectacular views is the fact that on top of this mountain the temple of the Moon can be found as well as some “impossible” terraces.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tips for Machu Picchu?</title>
      <link>https://www.guidetomachupicchu.com/questions/2019-12-28-tips-for-machu-picchu/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 14:18:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.guidetomachupicchu.com/questions/2019-12-28-tips-for-machu-picchu/</guid>
      <description>Some tips for Machu Picchu; officially one cannot take food into Machu Picchu. Small sandwiches for an improvised picnic on the guardsman house area are tolerated. Make sure that your walking stick has a rubber protection for the tip, if not this will not be allowed. Umbrellas are often not tolerated. There are no bathrooms on the site; only at the entrance. Only the tickets with Huayna Picchu or Montaña allow for a re-entrance to use the bathrooms.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>